I'm definitely guilty of being one of the
world's biggest hypocrites a lot of the
time when it comes to content creation.
This is Alfie, and this
is our ball ritual.
It is incredibly naive to think
that all of your social media posts
are going to do
really well. And in fact,
like most things in life,
there has to be a massive
element of course correction.
You have to look what works
and what doesn't.
You have to try new things out.
In fact, without trying new things out,
you can't see what works, and without
trying things out,
you can't see what doesn't work.
And every time a post does well,
we get an essential bit of feedback,
which allows
us to know what to double down on,
and what to avoid. But if you're like me,
you celebrate the ones doing well,
and you take the ones
that don't do well very personally.
Feel like a bit of a failure.
You carry it around with you all day,
and all it
takes is for a couple neggy comments.
It can quite literally throw you off for
almost the whole day.
"I don't... You..."
So there's an exercise that I'm trying,
and it doesn't work all the time, but I'm
really making a conscious effort to try
and get this to make myself feel better.
That's it.
It's not even necessarily going to make
your content do better.
It's just going to make you feel better,
and it's this.
Just before you send a post out,
ask yourself, "How well is this
going to do?" Because you're a better
judge of this than you think.
And be real with yourself. Be like, "Okay,
I think this one's got potential to do
really well." Or be real with yourself
and say, "Do you know what?
I actually don't think this one's going to
go that big, get that many views,
because it's more centered around
education or something niche." Especially
when
you're making niche content,
you need to be real with yourself and go,
"Out of the
population, only a small percentage
are even going to vibe with this call."
You
have to make a physical note.
Not a mental note, a physical note.
You've got to write it down.
You've got to write down the title of your
video or
whatever the concept is,
and say to yourself, "How well
is this going to do?" And
then what's going to happen is this.
When that video is a nine out of 10 on
YouTube, or when that video only gets half
the amount of views
that your usual post gets,
you go back to that and you say to
yourself, "Look, before posting this,
I knew it wasn't going to go viral.
I knew it wasn't going to have a massive
impact. I was testing something out.
I was trying something out."
And although it sounds oversimplified,
it makes you
feel so much better about it.
Case in point, this week,
I had to announce to people
that I'd invested in Manual, a UK-based
TRT company, and I knew I
was going to get some shit.
Because come to think of it,
we got so much abuse
when we launched Nootonic.
So I was like, [chuckles]
if bringing out a productivity drink
is going to get
people to hate us,
partnering with a UK TRT clinic, phwoar.
But I didn't do the exercise I told you
to.
I just kind of put it out there,
and then the comments come in,
they're negative.
I think I've lost like 1,000 YouTube subs.
But the thing is,
if I had just said to myself,
"James," last week, "how do you
think the video is going to go?" I would
have laughed and gone, "Do you know what?
I'm probably going to get a bit of abuse,
and I'm probably going to lose a couple
of thousand YouTube subs." I probably
would've said 5,000.
If I'd only done that and written it down,
I could look back on it today and go,
"Do you know what?
We're actually tracking ahead.
We're actually doing a bit better than
expected." But because I didn't do it,
the last couple of days I've been in the
worst mood.
Because as a creator, you always try
and mitigate the amount of abuse
that you're
going to get from people. And
if you're a creator
that doesn't take anything to
heart, well, you're a fucking psychopath.
And I'm kind of a bit gutted now
that I didn't do that sooner,
because I could have
made this whole scenario feel a lot
better.
Because this is the issue we have, right?
Humans have a negativity bias.
We will remember bad news better than good
news.
We are more drawn to negative stories than
positive stories.
We feel the psychological pain of losses
much, much more than the equivalent gain.
So for instance, if I
was walking here with Alf, and we
were to find $10 on the
floor,
it would make me a 5 out of 10 happy.
But if I was here with Alfie
and I lost $10, I'd be a 10 unhappy.
We're weird human beings,
the way we psychologically
are attached to things.
And when people unsubscribe,
they're just saying, "Do you know what?
I'm not really interested in what you're
selling anymore." But then off the back of
it, I look,
we've nearly got 1,000 people in the
Facebook group
for the TRT community, which is insane.
We're on track to have one of the biggest
community groups for men's health in the
UK within a week of launching.
But all I can think about is the abusive
comments and people
that don't understand what it is,
or people that I wouldn't
give time to in real life.
I'm letting them affect me
and ruin my day, and
my life is good. Look.
So when you're next creating content,
think to yourself, "Okay, am I trying out
something new? Is it a different hook?
Is it a different setup?
Is it a different subject?
Is it something that potentially could
react better, or
is it something that could potentially
react worse?
Am I expecting this to be the
best-performing video of the week?" And
if not, just
make a note of it, because then
when the video doesn't perform,
you're like, "Do
you know what?
That's exactly what I predicted."
When the video doesn't bring you
any clients, you go, "Exactly."
And maybe if you lose a couple subs,
you go, "Well,
I did say I was going to try something out
that could rub people the wrong way."
And what you're doing here
is you're not benefiting your socials,
you're not
benefiting your sales structure,
you're not benefiting much apart
from your mental health, which
is a pretty tricky part.
Because you can please 98% of the world,
and they give you a double tap, but you
don't really feel a double tap.
It doesn't really impact you.
When you look at likes on a comment,
you can't quantify 200 likes
or 1,000 likes or
20,000 likes,
but you can quantify a shitty comment.
You can make it real.
You can start to understand.
You start to paint it out in your mind
and think that
everyone hates you for it. Try that out.
Let me know how you go.
And the next time a post flops,
you can look in the mirror and go,
"Exactly as
I thought it was going to be."
If you found this video helpful,
you'll probably
love this one because the geniuses at
YouTube reckon that's one that you should
definitely watch. All right.
If you want to work with me,
I'll put some links in
the description. You know the rules.
Back to the dog throw. Dog throw?
Ball throw for the dog.